MICHELLE LYNN CHARRON

Boise, ID 83709 208-316-2203

michelle.charron93@gmail.com https://github.com/MCharron93 https://www.linkedin.com/in/michelle-charron/

A passionate full-stack software developer with over 500 hours technical experience in multiple frameworks. 5+ years of quantitative and qualitative research experience. Strong analytical practices balanced with leadership and data-driven decision making.

Experience

Full-Stack Software Developer

Boise CodeWorks, Sep 2020 - Jan 2021

- Created and designed full-stack web applications through HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript, Node.js, Vue.js, Express, Auth0, C#/ DotNet Core, MySQL, BootStrap, Mongoose, and MongoDB
- Built with Object Orientated Program languages to create reactive front-end views and utilizing MVC patterns to create dynamic back-end servers
- Ensure project progression through Scrum management by initiating daily standups with team
- Provide debugging support through verbal feedback and troubleshooting complex coding errors
- Orchestrated code review sessions and assisted in code revisions for final deployment launch

Specimen Processing Specialist

Analytical Laboratories, Feb 2020 to Sep 2020

- Received and processed samples of various media
- Preserved and maintained sample viability through laboratory standards
- Transcribed and digitalized laboratory records for sample analysis
- Maintained and secured all electronic records to be free of errors during routine transcription audits

Direct Care Staff

Teton Supported Living, Sep 2017 to Feb 2020

- Provide guidance in daily living tasks, medication handling, and aiding in social interactions while maintaining healthy relationships
- Provide safe behavioral monitoring and mentoring to various participants
- Data collection and entry for behavioral based program implementation and goal monitoring
- Compiled monthly reports for program effectiveness with behavioral observation log entries

Educational Background

Certificate of Completion from BOISE CODEWORKS - Boise, ID, Sep 2020 to Jan 2021

• Full-Stack Software Development

Bachelor's of Science, Psychology from BOISE STATE UNIVERSITY - Boise, ID Jan 2018 to Dec 2019: Conferral Date 12/21/2019

- Teaching Assistantship for Behavioral Statistics
- Research Assistantship for Data Analyst at Northwest Neurobehavioral Health

Additional Skills and Merits

- Advanced knowledge of quantitative/qualitative statistics and research methodology.
- Gained a deep understanding of data analytics and teaching experience to diverse groups of students and team members
- Specialized in scoring, interpreting and presentation of statistical findings through technical report writing